<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thibaut Tauveron</title>
    <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thibaut Tauveron</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttauveron.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy traefik in GKE using (L7) Google HTTP/S Load balancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/traefik_behind_google_l7_load_balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/traefik_behind_google_l7_load_balancer/</guid>
      <description>Using Google Load Balancers in GKE Google Cloud proposes multiple types of load balancers and we can use those in GKE.
Usually, the first thing we do in GKE when we need to expose a service is to set its type to type: LoadBalancer. Under the hood, GCP automatically creates a Regional External TCP/UDP Network Load Balancer (L4) that gives us an IP address in Kubernetes to reach our service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring a TCP proxy between networks in GCP</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/configuring_tcp_proxy_between_networks_in_gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/configuring_tcp_proxy_between_networks_in_gcp/</guid>
      <description>I worked on an interesting challenge recently and I thought it would be nice to write a blog post about it!
A little bit of context first, there are two Google Cloud projects (which could be in two different organizations) and each one of those have their own network. A client in Project A needs to access an API in project B but this API is not publicly exposed for security reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Hello world!
My name is Thibaut, I work in software engineering, broadly speaking.
I&amp;rsquo;m specialized in DevOps practices and I like hacking around with various tech.
I decided to start a blog in order to document my learnings and talk about things I&amp;rsquo;m interested in, engineering being my main focus.
Hope this blog can inspire some readers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
