<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thibaut Tauveron</title>
    <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thibaut Tauveron</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hive - Tryhackme</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/tryhackme_thehive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/tryhackme_thehive/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know about tryhackme.com, it&amp;rsquo;s an online platform for learning cyber security hands-on. Multiple &amp;ldquo;rooms&amp;rdquo; are available to get better in cybersecurity. Usually, a room consists in a vulnerable system running in a virtual machine that you can access through a private ip. Your goal is to get flags hidden in the system by discovering and exploiting various vulnerabilities. Users can also propose their own rooms, it makes it quite fun to solve other people challenges and share knowledge!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse engineering Siebel Test Automation Jenkins plugin</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/siebel_test_automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/siebel_test_automation/</guid>
      <description>I have recently been helping a Swedish insurance company to improve their DevOps capabilities. Like many other large companies, they are using an Oracle product called Siebel as their CRM and one of the challenges is to introduce smoke testing through test automation for Siebel.
Oracle provides different tools to orchestrate this test automation in Siebel and this article has been a great resource for me to understand in more details how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palsforlife - Tryhackme</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/tryhackme_palsforlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/tryhackme_palsforlife/</guid>
      <description>TryHackMe is a platform to learn cyber security hands-on, they make it really fun to solve challenges and learn new tools &amp;amp; techniques. Making my way through challenges, I noticed there was only one room involving Kubernetes.
As Kubernetes has gained quite some popularity over the last few years, k8s clusters are now interesting targets so it&amp;rsquo;s good to learn how a cluster can be compromised to be better at securing it, that&amp;rsquo;s why I designed and proposed a room called palsforlife about k8s (and world of warcraft!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A basic openvpn bash wrapper with completion</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/vpn_bash_helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 17:20:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/vpn_bash_helper/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working with multiple openvpn environments in Linux and while I enjoy working with the command line, it can be cumbersome to manage different connections through the openvpn cli.
My ideal VPN cli would be super simple : connect, disconnect and bash completion for everything.
As cumbersome + linux often leads to automation, my solution involves a little bit of bash :-)
Install The following code needs to be sourced. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve added it to my .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capitalizing on the Linux commands history</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/capitalizing_on_the_linux_commands_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/capitalizing_on_the_linux_commands_history/</guid>
      <description>Working with Linux I tend to forget commands that I’m not using regularly. I also don&amp;rsquo;t like to retype a long command. Fortunately, the bash history can be used to find back those previous commands.
The basic usage is to cycle through the bash history with the up and down keys, we also can use Ctrl-R to type the beginning of a command and autocomplete it according to the history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy traefik in GKE using (L7) Google HTTP/S Load balancer</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/traefik_behind_google_l7_load_balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/traefik_behind_google_l7_load_balancer/</guid>
      <description>Using Google Load Balancers in GKE Google Cloud proposes multiple types of load balancers and we can use those in GKE.
Usually, the first thing we do in GKE when we need to expose a service is to set its type to type: LoadBalancer. Under the hood, GCP automatically creates a Regional External TCP/UDP Network Load Balancer (L4) that gives us an IP address in Kubernetes to reach our service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A TCP proxy between networks in GCP</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/configuring_tcp_proxy_between_networks_in_gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/configuring_tcp_proxy_between_networks_in_gcp/</guid>
      <description>I worked on an interesting challenge recently and I thought it would be nice to write a blog post about it!
A little bit of context first, there are two Google Cloud projects (which could be in two different organizations) and each one of those have their own network. A client in Project A needs to access an API in project B but this API is not publicly exposed for security reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.ttauveron.com/posts/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Hello world!
My name is Thibaut, I work in software engineering, broadly speaking.
I&amp;rsquo;m specialized in DevOps practices and I like hacking around with various tech.
I decided to start a blog in order to document my learnings and talk about things I&amp;rsquo;m interested in, engineering being my main focus.
Hope this blog can inspire some readers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
